Yessenia Vieyra

Smithfield, UT 84335 vieyrayessenia8@gmail.com (913)208-1627

Summary

My name is Yessenia and I am a hardworking individual who has spent the last six years of my professional career in property management. Property management has taught me a long list of skills that I know will be useful and make me an asset to your team. From operations management, marketing, budgets, auditing, accounting, customer service, and problem solving. I have become a great multi-tasker that knows how to organize a number of high priority tasks in a day and communicate effectively with my peers for the most efficient solutions and task completion. I believe my positive attitude and strong work ethic has helped me become a top performer in every organization/company I have been a part of. I am currently looking for an opportunity to change careers and start a career in the tech world. I recently received my full stack development certificate from the University Of Utah. I am ready to apply the skills I have learned and continue to learn more. I look forward to an interview opportunity.

Skills

- Relationship building and rapport
- Business processes and procedures
- Housing Regulations
- Administrative Regulations
- Budget Preparation
- Multitasking and prioritizing
- Critical thinking
- Javascript

- Front-end programming: CSS & HTML
- Back-end and Database skills
- Databases: Nosql, MongoDB & Mysql
- 5 years experience using Entrata & Property Management Software
- User experience design

Work Experience

Assistant Property Manager (Full-Time) Kartchner Property Management (Strata

Apartments) - Logan, UT

October 2020 to August 2023

- Collect monthly rent and follow up on all delinquencies (past, current, and notice)
- · Send accounts to collections and eviction if needed.
- Create renewal offers, negotiate renewal offers if possible and create renewal leases.
- · Complete the move out process from day notice is given to the determination of deposit refunds or amounts due.
- Schedule appointments throughout the day and be prepared for prospect/resident drop-ins throughout the day that have not been scheduled.
- Problem solving resident complaints.
- Assist in leasing when needed such as touring prospective residents, and troubleshooting Entrata for prospects & residents when the user is having issues navigating the software.
- · Assist with the property manager workload such as reports, property maintenance, projects and budgeting.
- Manage brand marketing on social media and advertising platforms. .
- Maintain property occupancy 95% or higher.
- Event planning for resident events (resident appreciation).

Assistant Property Manager/Leasing Consultant (Full-Time) FourSite Property

Management - Kansas City, MO April 2019 to September 2020

- Collect rent payments monthly and follow up on all delinquencies (past, current, and notice)/ Send accounts to collections and eviction if needed.
- Create renewal offers, negotiate renewal offers if possible and create renewal leases.
- · Complete the move out process from the day notice is given to the determination of deposit refunds or amounts due.
- Schedule all pre-move out inspections and final move out inspections.
- · Problem solving resident complaints.
- Assist in leasing when needed such as touring prospective residents and completing an applicant file.
- Process and file away payments made in the office.
- Assist with the property manager's work load such as CMA's, billing, bids, weekly reports and approving/denying files when property manager is absent.
- Create payment plans if needed, send weekly reports on delinquencies and send final move out statements for approval to Regional Manager.
- Help assist in the planning of monthly resident events to show resident appreciation.
- · Assist in the auditing of renewal and application files to ensure that the process has been completed correctly.

Administrative Assistant/Leasing Consultant (Full-Time)

KC Commercial and Residential Management - Kansas City, MO February 2018 to April 2019

- · Billed vendor Invoices.
- · Managed utility on and off status for vacant/occupied properties.
- Completed the move in and move out process for past and future residents.
- Payroll for vendors (quick books)
- Data Entry (quick books)
- Experience with Tenant Turner, Appfolio Software, and Entrata Software.
- Marketing
- Experience creating work orders for residents.
- Problem solving various complaints from owners and residents.
- Handled lead applications and kept close contact with all leasing agents to manage the process effectively.
- · Experience with high call volume.
- Experience communicating often with leasing leads and owners for leasing updates such as tours and leases.

Education

Full Stack Development Bootcamp

University of Utah - Utah

April 2023

Associates Of Arts Degree (A.A)

Metropolitan Community College - Kansas City, MO May 2017

High school Diploma

Smith-Cotton High School - Sedalia, MO

May 2015